American Colony in Jerusalem Collection
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Part I: Topical File, 1871-2004 (Box I:1-3)
  - In the Holy Land
    - Bible belonging to Horatio Gates Spafford (1828-1888), circa 1870s
    - Letter from Horatio Gates Spafford (1828-1888) to Charles Piazza Smith, 1887
    - “The Great Pyramid of Egypt–The Mightiest Wonder on Earth,” from Our Rest and Signs of the Times, no. 11, 1882
    - Map of Jerusalem, undated See Oversize
    - Correspondence between A. Loivy and Horatio Gates Spafford (1828-1888), 1885
    - Letter from Anna T. Spafford to Mrs. Morse, 1909
    - Letter to Theodore Roosevelt (1858-1919) from the American Colony, 1906
    - “Our American Colony in Jerusalem” by Alexander Hume Ford, Appleton's Magazine, 1906
    - Letter to Alexander Hume Ford from the American Colony, 1906
    - “Americans Lead in Jerusalem Progress” by William T. Ellis, 1913
  - The American Colony at Work
    - “In Memoriam” keepsake with pressed flowers, undated
    - List of antiquities sent to University of Pennsylvania Museum, Philadelphia, Pa., 1913
    - Postcards of the Holy Land, 1921, undated
    - Scrapbook of American Colony clippings, 1871-1942
      - Bound vol. See Oversize
      - Loose items removed from scrapbook See Oversize
    - Business card, John D. Whiting, United States deputy consul, Jerusalem, undated
    - “The Chief Industries of the American Colony, Jerusalem, at the Present Time,” 1907
    - Letter from David Fairchild to John D. Whiting, 1916
    - Letter from Gilbert Hovey Grosvenor to John D. Whiting, 1915
  - The Locust Plague
    - Locust album, 1915 See Oversize
    - Photograph of Bertha Spafford Vester, John Vester, Louise Vester, and Jemal Pasha, circa 1915
  - World War I
    - Photograph album, 1914-1917 See Oversize
    - Scrapbook of Fannie L. Koster regarding American Colony, circa 1908-1924 See Oversize
    - Wartime pass issued by Ottoman Turkish forces, 1916-1917
    - Turkish lira note
    - Movement order, Kantara Military Railway, for John D. Whiting, British intelligence, 1918
    - American Colony nursing corps
      - Names of nurses, 1917
      - Night pass for nurses, circa 1915-1917
      - Photograph, circa 1915-1917
    - Hospital record, 1916 See Oversize
    - Manifesto and other printed announcements, 1882, 1896, 1905, 1914 See Oversize
    - Miscellaneous passes and permits, 1914-1917
    - Note from A. F. Bernard Shaw to American Hospital, Jerusalem, 1917
  - Wartime Aid (Box I:3)
    - School of Handicrafts and Dressmaking
      - Brochures and photographs, circa 1920s
      - Lace sample book, undated
    - Report of the Syrian and Palestine Relief Fund sewing rooms and Christian Herald Relief Fund lace industry, circa 1918
    - Account book of money received by Mr. Trowbridge, 1918
    - Balance sheet for distribution of Charitable Funds, Feb- Apr. 1918
    - Loud, Edward F.
      - Account of and distribution of Loud Fund, 1916-1917
      - Letter from John D. Whiting to Edward F. Loud, 1918(?)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1916-1918
      - “Photograph of Mr. and Mrs. Edward Loud at their island home in Michigan,” undated
  - Continuing Relief Work
    - Christian Herald Orphanage
      - Photograph album, 1918-1927, (2 folders)
      - Register of children, 1921-1923
    - Appeals to Bertha Spafford Vester for aid, 1918-1921
    - Spafford Children's Center
      - Pamphlet, undated
      - Photographs, 2004, undated
    - Documents regarding relief and charitable work
      - Miscellaneous activities, 1915-1922, undated
      - Nonsectarian nature of work, 1920, undated
- Part I: Oversize, 1871-1942 (Box I:OV 1- OV 7)
  Draft of hymn, map, scrapbooks, photograph album, hospital record, and printed matter.
  Arranged and described according to the series, containers, and folders from which the items were removed.
  - Topical file (Box I:OV 1)
    - On to Jerusalem
      - “Perilous Times,” circa 1879 (Container I:1)
    - In the Holy Land
      - Map of Jerusalem, undated (Container I:2)
    - The American Colony at Work (Box I:OV 2*)
      *Administratively restricted
      - Scrapbook of American Colony clippings, 1871-1942
        - Bound vol. (Container I:2)
        - Loose items removed from scrapbook (Container I:2) (Box I:OV 3)
    - The Locust Plague (Box I:OV 4*)
      - Locust Album, 1915 (Container I:2)
    - World War I (Box I:OV 5*)
      - Photograph album, 1914-1917 (Container (I:2)
      - Scrapbook of Fannie L. Koster regarding American Colony, circa 1908-1924 (Container I:2) (Box I:OV 6*)
      - Hospital record, 1916 (Container I:2) (Box I:OV 7)
      - Manifesto and other printed announcements, 1882, 1896, 1905, 1914 (Container I:2)
- Part II: Our Jerusalem, circa 1786-1942 (Box II:1-9)
  Correspondence, notes, writings, lectures, printed matter, and other papers compiled by Bertha Spafford Vester as resource files for her book, Our Jerusalem.
  Most files are arranged chronologically by year. Others are grouped by type of material and therein chronologically.
  - Biographies, 1873, 1941, undated (Box II:1)
  - Chapter on Moslem girls school, draft, undated
  - Chronological file
    - 1850-1873, (12 folders)
    - 1874-1892, (20 folders) (Box II:2)
    - 1893-1902 See also Oversize, (14 folders) (Box II:3)
    - 1903-1919, (17 folders) (Box II:4)
    - 1920-1924 See also Container II: 8, 1922, (11 folders) (Box II:5)
    - 1925-1930, (12 folders) (Box II:6)
    - 1931-1938 See also Container II:9, 1931, (13 folders) (Box II:7)
    - 1939-1942, (4 folders) (Box II:8)
  - Lectures, 1927, undated
  - Miscellany, circa 1786, 1850, 1891, 1918-1922, 1938, undated, (3 folders)
  - Personal correspondence
    - Family letters
      - 1922, 1930 See also Container II: 5, 1922, (4 folders)
      - 1931 See also Container II:7, 1931, (3 folders) (Box II:9)
    - Spafford, Jacob E., letters to H. D. Titus, 1923-1930, (3 folders)
- Part II: Bertha Spafford Vester Diaries, 1920-1968 (Box II:9-31)
  Diaries and folders of loose items that were removed from each volume.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - 1920-1924, (3 folders) (Box II:9)
  - 1925-1926 See also Oversize, (4 folders) (Box II:10)
  - 1927, (2 folders) (Box II:11)
  - 1925-1928 “year to year” volume, (2 folders)
  - 1929, (2 folders) (Box II:12)
  - 1930, (1 folder) (Box II:13)
  - 1931, (2 folders)
  - 1932, (2 folders) (Box II:14)
  - 1933, (1 folder) (Box II:15)
  - 1934, (1 folder) (Box II:16)
  - 1935
    - Diary See Oversize
    - Loose items See also Oversize
  - 1936
    - Jan.-July
      - Diary See Oversize
      - Loose items
    - July-Dec., (2 folders)
  - 1937 (Box II:17)
    - Diary See Oversize
    - Loose items
  - 1938
    - Diary no. 1
      - Diary See Oversize
      - Loose items
    - Diary no. 2
  - 1939, (2 folders)
  - 1940-1942, (6 folders) (Box II:18)
  - 1943-1944, (4 folders) (Box II:19)
  - 1945, (1 folder) (Box II:20)
  - 1946-1947, (6 folders)
  - 1948-1949, (5 folders) (Box II:21)
  - 1950, (5 folders) (Box II:22)
  - 1951, (3 folders) (Box II:23)
  - 1952, (1 folder) (Box II:24)
  - 1953, (3 folders)
  - 1954, (6 folders) (Box II:25)
  - 1955, (3 folders) (Box II:26)
  - 1956, (1 folder); (6 folders) (Box II:27)
  - 1957, (6 folders) (Box II:28)
  - 1958, (4 folders) (Box II:29)
  - 1959, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:30)
  - 1960-1961, (3 folders)
  - 1962, (2 folders) (Box II:31)
  - 1963-1968, (7 folders)
- Part II: American Colony Members, 1810-2006 (Box II:32-34)
  Correspondence, diaries, notes, financial records, wills, printed matter, registers of American Colony members, and other papers.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of person or type of material and therein chronologically.
  - Andersson, Ana, 1945-1947, undated (Box II:32)
  - Baldwin, Norman, 1928-1935, 2006
  - Goldenthal, Maurice, 1911, 1926-1931, undated
  - Gould, Amelia, 1856, 1876-1880, 1887-1898, 1905-1914, undated, (4 folders)
  - Henwood, Susana J., 1874, 1882, 1894-1897, 1936-1938, 1949, undated, (3 folders)
  - Larsson, H. L. (“Lars”), 1922-1931, undated
  - Levy, Christina Larsson, and Nils Larsson, 1934-1935, 1948-1954
  - Lind, L. E. (“Lars”), 1922-1930, undated
  - Lind, Nils, 1922
  - Lind, Olaf E., 1922-1928, undated
  - Matson, G. Eric (Box II:33)
    - Correspondence, 1932
    - Diary, 1928-1937
  - Matson, G. Olaf, 1920-1933, undated, (3 folders)
  - Matsson, Rachel, 1947-1950
  - Meyers, Charles, and family, 1925, 1931-1937
  - Registers
    - American Colony of Jerusalem members and members of the Council of the American Colony of Jerusalem, 1932-1933, undated
    - Birthday book, 1942
  - Shelburg, G. E. (“Enor”) and Bessie, 1918-1926
  - Smith, Carrie Jonsson, 1891-1898, 1908, 1914-1916, 1928-1932
  - Spafford, Anna T., 1860, 1881, 1922-1923, 1931-1940, 1978, 1993, undated, (2 folders)
  - Spafford, Horatio Gates (1828-1888), 1810-1811, 1830, 1870-1873, 1882-1886, 1903-1909, 1926, 1947(?), 1968, 1981, 1993, undated, (3 folders) (Box II:34)
  - Spafford, Jacob E.
    - Correspondence, 1913, 1927
    - Financial papers, 1890-1922, undated, (2 folders)
    - Miscellany, 1903, 1912, 1925-1933, undated
  - Strand, Alvide, 1931-1932, undated
  - Sylvester, Mary Maria, 1896-1899, 1920, undated, (3 folders)
  - Whiting, John D., 1891-1893, 1910, 1942-1945, 1951-1953, undated
  - Wills of members, 1926-1932, undated
- Part II: Business and Legal Files, 1811-2006 (Box II:35-40)
  Correspondence, memoranda, minutes, legal documents, financial records, and other business documents relating to the American Colony and the Spafford family.
  Grouped into files pertaining to the American Colony and those concerning the Spafford family and therein alphabetically by topic or type of material.
  - American Colony (Box II:35)
    - American Colony Aid Association
      - Miscellany, 1931, 1937, 1950
      - Trip to the United States, 1938
        - Correspondence, (5 folders)
        - Miscellany
    - American Colony Hotels See Restricted
      - Miscellany, 1966-1973, undated
      - Transfer of shares, 1954, 1962-1971, undated
    - American Colony of Jerusalem
      - Corporate reorganization See Restricted
        - Formation of AMCOL, 1979-1984, (2 folders)
        - Plan by Horatio Vester, 1954, undated
        - Tax and other issues, 1978-1982, undated, (2 folders)
        - Transfer documents, 1983-1984
      - Financial reports, 1932-1941 See Restricted
      - Meetings See Restricted
        - Council, 1933-1936, 1942-1952
        - General and extraordinary, 1929-1955, 1962-1982, (7 folders)
      - Miscellany, 1952-1980 See Restricted, (4 folders)
    - Miscellaneous issues
      - Howorth, Caroline Eade, business with Frutiger Bank, Jerusalem, 1888-1893, 1921-1923
      - Miller, Susanna, pension claim, 1894-1897, undated
      - Partition of land, 1931-1933 See Restricted
      - Powers of attorney, 1887, 1930-1932 See Restricted
    - Naseef v. Vester, 1924-1934
    - Receipts, 1881-1904, (7 folders)
    - Reorganization and dissent (Box II:36)
      - American corporation
        - Correspondence, 1927-1930, (2 folders)
        - Miscellaneous documents, 1929-1930
        - Proposed amendments, 1930, undated
      - Arbitration
        - Award, ruling, and other documents
          - 1929-1931, (2 folders)
          - Undated See Restricted
        - Bildt, Harold Knut Clarence de, 1929-1930
        - Costs, 1930-1932
        - Perrott, C. H., 1930-1931
        - Richardson, S. O., 1930-1931
      - Auster, Daniel, 1927-1930
      - Charitable trust lawsuit
        - Affidavits, 1928-1930, undated
          - Court, Jerusalem, 1928-1930, (2 folders)
        - Keith-Roach, Edward, 1930, undated
        - Memoranda, 1930, undated
        - Statements by American Colony members, undated, (2 folders) (Box II:37)
        - Supreme Court, Court of Appeal, Jerusalem, 1929-1930, undated
      - Cooperative scheme, 1930-1931, undated
      - Distribution of property
        - Dissolution of Mechanical Department, 1930-1931
        - Miscellaneous distributions, 1930-1931 See Restricted
        - Transfer of Vester house and land, 1931 See Restricted
      - Loan, 1931, (2 folders)
      - Meetings and resolutions
        - General meeting (May 28,1930), vote on separation, 1930, 1936
        - Miscellaneous, 1926-1930
      - Memoranda on disputes within the American Colony, undated, (2 folders)
      - Money owed by minority group to majority group, 1930-1934, undated (Box II:38)
      - Newspaper articles and related correspondence
        - Ellis, William T., 1931-1932, 1938
        - Miscellaneous, 1918, 1924-1932, undated
      - “On Holy Paths,” by Laura Petri, translated from Swedish, 1931, undated
      - Townsend, Arthur O., 1928-1934, 1984, (5 folders)
    - Russell and Co., accountants
      - General
        - 1930-1931, (5 folders)
        - 1947 See Restricted
      - Whiting, John D., 1930-1931, undated (Box II:39)
    - Saffi, Michael, and land, 1920-1935 See Restricted
    - Swedish Evangelical Church of Hyde Park, Chicago, Ill., 1886-1888, 1895-1899, undated
    - Vester and Co.
      - American Colony Stores
        - Jerusalem store, “Plan of Jerusalem Issued by Vester & Company American Colony Stores,” undated
        - New York, N.Y., store
          - Business papers, 1922, 1929-1941, undated, (2 folders)
          - Correspondence, 1930-1933, (6 folders)
        - Registration of firm, 1919-1928 See Restricted
      - Beirut, Lebanon, office See Restricted (Box II:40)
        - Financial accounts, 1961-1965
        - Miscellany, 1958-1968
        - Separation from American Colony Hotels, 1961-1962
      - Jerusalem office See Restricted
        - Financial accounts, 1962-1968
        - Miscellany, 1960-1967
      - Miscellany, 1962-1976 See Restricted
      - Taylor, Mervyn, solicitor, 1969-1970 See Restricted
  - Spafford family
    - Chicago, Ill., property, litigation, 1878, 1885-1908, undated, (2 folders)
    - Miscellany, 1865-1871 See also Oversize
    - Spafford v. Spafford, 1811, 2006
- Part II: Chronological File, 1893-1968 (Box II:41-45)
  Correspondence, legal documents, notes, printed matter and other papers concerning the activities of the American Colony.
  Arranged chronologically by year.
  - 1893-1907, (16 folders) (Box II:41)
  - 1908-1912, (11 folders) (Box II:42)
  - 1913-1914, (10 folders) (Box II:43)
  - 1915-1920, (14 folders) (Box II:44)
  - 1924-1938, 1944-1950, 1965-1968, (18 folders) (Box II:45)
- Part II: Miscellany, 1869-2005 (Box II:45-46)
  Hymns, poetry, and other writings by Horatio Gates Spafford (1828-1888), notes, oral history transcript, photographs, and printed matter.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material and therein chronologically.
  - Handwritten notes, undated (Box II:45)
  - Hymns, poems, and other writings by Horatio Gates Spafford (1828-1888)
    - Bible study, undated
    - Hymns and poems, circa early 1870s-1887, undated See also Oversize, (8 folders)
    - Letter describing his sister's biblical interpretations and his beliefs, 1879 (Box II:46)
    - Notebook, 1869
  - Letter from Charles Green, 1884
  - Oral history interview with Valentine Vester, 2005
  - Photographs, 1873, 1908-1909, circa 1928, 1937, undated, (3 folders)
  - Printed matter
    - Ferry Hall, Lake Forest, Ill., 1926, undated, (2 folders)
    - The House-Top Saint by Mrs. J. D. Chaplin, undated
    - Memorial cards, undated
    - Miscellaneous, 1981-1982
    - Newspapers in Arabic, 1963-1967
- Part II: Restricted, 1887-1984 (Box II:R47-R49)
  Business and legal files.
  - Business and Legal Files (Box II:R47)
    - American Colony
      - American Colony Hotels (Container II:35)
        - Miscellany, 1966-1973, undated
        - Transfer of shares, 1954, 1962-1971, undated
      - American Colony of Jerusalem
        - Corporate reorganization (Container II:35)
          - Formation of AMCOL, 1979-1984, (2 folders)
          - Plan by Horatio Vester, 1954, undated
          - Tax and other issues, 1978-1982, undated, (2 folders)
          - Transfer documents, 1983-1984
        - Financial reports, 1932-1941 (Container II:35)
        - Meetings
          - Council, 1933-1936, 1942-1952 (Container II:35)
          - General and extraordinary, 1929-1955, 1962-1982 (Container II:35), (7 folders) (Box II:R48)
        - Miscellany, 1952-1980 (Container II:35), (4 folders)
      - Miscellaneous issues (Container II:35) (Box II:R49)
        - Partition of land, 1931-1933
        - Powers of attorney, 1887, 1930-1932
      - Reorganization and dissent
        - Arbitration (Container II:36)
          - Award, ruling, and other documents, undated
        - Distribution of property (Container II:37)
          - Miscellaneous distributions, 1930-1931
          - Transfer of Vester house and land, 1931
      - Russell and Co., accountants
        - General, 1947 (Container II:38)
      - Saffi, Michael, and land, 1920-1935 (Container II:39)
      - Vester and Co.
        - American Colony Stores
          - Registration of firm, 1919-1928 (Container II:39)
        - Beirut, Lebanon, office (Container II:40)
          - Financial accounts, 1961-1965
          - Miscellany, 1958-1968
          - Separation from American Colony Hotels, 1961-1962
        - Jerusalem office (Container II:40)
          - Financial accounts, 1962-1968
          - Miscellany, 1960-1967
        - Miscellany, 1962-1976 (Container II:40)
        - Taylor, Mervyn, solicitor, 1969-1970 (Container II:40)
- Part II: Oversize, 1866-1938 (Box II:OV 1-OV 8)
  Diaries, hymns, poems, and other writings by Horatio Gates Spafford (1828-1888), maps, and printed matter.
  - Our Jerusalem (Box II:OV 1)
    - Chronological file
      - 1896 (Container II:3)
  - Bertha Spafford Vester Diaries
    - 1925 (Container II:10)
    - 1935 (Box II:OV 2)
      - Diary (Container II:16)
      - Loose items (Container II:16) (Box II:OV 3)
    - 1936 (Box II:OV 4)
      - Jan.-July
        - Diary (Container II:16)
    - 1937 (Container II:17) (Box II:OV 5)
    - 1938 (Container II:17) (Box II:OV 6)
  - Business and Legal Files (Box II:OV 7)
    - Spafford family
      - Miscellany, 1866-1870 (Container II:40)
  - Miscellany (Box II:OV 8)
    - Hymns, poems, and other writings by Horatio Gates Spafford (1828-1888)
      - Hymns and poems, undated (Container II:45)
- Part III: Bertha Spafford Vester Files, 1861-1991 (Box III:1-III:9)
  Correspondence, writings, photographs, passes, permits, financial papers, scrapbooks, and other papers.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material, name or topic, and therein chronologically.
  - Correspondence (Box III:1)
    - American Colony members
      - Adams, Mary Louise (Sister Miriam), 1930-1934
      - Aitkins, Annie, 1892-1895
      - Anderson, Ellen, 1909, circa 1919-1922, 1945-1947, (2 folders)
      - “A” miscellaneous, 1895-1898, 1930
      - Baldwin, Edward and Ella, 1890, 1920, 1991
      - Baldwin, Grace, 1931-1935
      - Baldwin, Norman and Christina, 1923-1932, 1946
      - Cuff, Samuel H., 1923-1931
      - “D-H” miscellaneous, 1909, 1920, 1927-1931, 1938, 1944
      - Goldenthal, Maurice and Ruth, 1926-1937
      - Larsson, Edith and Lewis, 1926-1932
      - Larsson, Katrina, 1929-1933, 1942-1943
      - Levy, Nils, 1929-1931
      - Lind, Anna Grace, 1946
      - Lind, Effie and Lars, 1926-1927, 1934
      - Lind, Olof and Astrid, 1922-1928, 1935, 1941
      - “L” miscellaneous, 1920-1934, undated
      - Matson, Edith Yantiss, 1930-1934
      - Matson, Eva, 1930-1934
      - Matson, G. Eric, 1948
      - Matson, Olof and Rachel, 1929-1945
      - Meyers, Charlie and Carrie, and family, 1921-1936, (2 folders)
      - “M” miscellaneous, 1890, 1909, 1921, 1928-1931, 1942 (Box III:2)
      - Naseef, Fareed and Flora, 1896, 1922-1928, 1935
      - Piazza family, 1909, 1918, 1931
      - Shelburg, Bessie, 1920, 1928
      - Shelburg, G. E. (Enor), includes letters from Anna Spafford, 1922-1926, 1933-1934
      - Strand, Alvilde, 1925-1930
      - Vester, Horatio, 1947
      - Whiting, Spafford, 1928, 1930
      - Yantiss, Anita and Jesse, 1926, 1932-1935
    - Condolence letters, 1942-1943, (5 folders)
    - Family
      - 1928-1929, (4 folders)
      - 1930-1931, 1963, (2 folders) (Box III:3)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Allenby, Edmund Henry Hynman Allenby, Viscount, and Mabel, 1918-1931, 1940
      - Astor, Nancy Witcher Langhorne Astor, Viscountess, 1929-1931, 1937
      - “A” miscellaneous, 1924, 1933
      - “B” miscellaneous, 1920-1935, 1946
      - Catt, Carrie Chapman, undated
      - “C-E” miscellaneous, 1922-1928, 1951
      - Fawcett, Millicent Garrett, Dame, 1925-1927
      - “F” miscellaneous, 1927, 1947
      - Griffiths, G., 1946
      - “G” miscellaneous, 1925, 1939, 1946
      - “H-K” miscellaneous, 1926-1928, 1935, 1944-1947
      - Lagerlöff, Selma, 1925-1937
      - Linson, Corwin K., 1949
      - Money, Arthur and Euphemia, 1919-1931
      - “M” miscellaneous, 1921-1946
      - “N-Q” miscellaneous, 1918, 1926, 1935-1940, 1946
      - “R” miscellaneous, 1924-1931, 1944-1946
      - Samuel, Herbert Louis Samuel, Viscount, and Beatrice, 1920-1931
      - Shea, John, Sir, 1920-1946
      - Stebbins, George C., 1922-1927
      - Storrs, Ronald, Sir, 1923-1926, 1933-1935
      - “S” miscellaneous, 1923-1927
      - Thomas, Lowell, circa 1926, 1931, 1937-1940, 1947
      - “T” miscellaneous, 1937, 1944
      - Ustinov, Magdalena von, 1922
      - Wauchope, Arthur, 1933-1938
      - “W” miscellaneous, 1923-1925, 1935
      - Unidentified, 1927
    - “Peculiar letters worth keeping,” 1919-1923
    - Regarding book of wild flower paintings, 1922-1934
    - Regarding Naseef v. Vester, 1931
    - Birthday book, undated (Box III:4)
    - Invitations, 1960-1961, (2 folders)
    - Items to accompany 1934 diary, 1934
    - Membership cards and receipts, 1918-1921, 1955-1967, undated, (2 folders)
    - Mementos from death of Frederick Vester, 1942
    - Naturalization file
      - Correspondence, 1922-1931, 1940, 1947, undated, (4 folders)
      - Miscellany, 1920-1931, undated, (2 folders) (Box III:5)
    - Passes and permits, 1946-1965
    - Passports
      - Lind, Anna Grace, 1955
      - Vester, Bertha Spafford, 1931-1935, 1959-1965
    - Photographs
      - American Cemetery, Mount Zion, 1905
      - Chicago, Ill., scenes, circa 1870s
      - Dedication of wing in memory of Jacob Spafford, Anna Spafford Baby Home and Mothercraft Training Centre, 1937
      - Hornby, Jack, undated
      - Jerusalem, 1933, 1948, undated, (2 folders)
      - Miscellaneous, 1870, 1908, 1949, undated
      - Money, Arthur, undated
      - Spafford family, 1861-1880s
      - Urquhart, William W., 1873-1878
      - Vester, Bertha Spafford, 1890s, 1934, 1943-1946, 1954-1968, undated, (3 folders) (Box III:6)
      - Vester, Bertha Spafford and Frederick Vester, undated
      - Vester, Frederick, circa 1928-1930, undated
    - Presidential signatures, undated
    - Press clippings
      - Miscellaneous, 1960-1961
      - Regarding Bertha Spafford Vester, 1899, 1968
    - Prints and printed matter, 1918, 1958, undated See also Oversize
    - Relief and charitable work file
      - Christian Alliance, 1918-1921
      - Miscellany, 1916-1921, (2 folders)
      - Tuberculosis fund
        - Correspondence, 1919-1921
        - Financial papers, 1919-1920, (3 folders)
        - Notebook, circa 1919
    - Scrapbooks (Box III:7)
      - 1932-1933
      - 1934-1960, (2 folders)
      - 1963-1967 See also Oversize, (2 folders)
    - Test on religious manuscripts, undated
    - Trip to Persia (Iran), 1927
    - Visiting cards, undated
    - Wild flowers sent to Dwight D. Eisenhower, 1953
  - Speeches and writings (Box III:8)
    - Notes, undated
    - Radio broadcasts
      - Correspondence and contracts, 1936-1939
      - Texts, 1936-1938, undated, (3 folders)
    - Writings
      - Miscellaneous, 1918-1920, 1950-1964, undated, (4 folders)